<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/</id><title>Techno Tim</title><subtitle>Documentation for Techno Tim videos for all your copy pasta needs!</subtitle> <updated>2021-06-20T11:08:20-05:00</updated> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> <uri>https://techno-tim.github.io/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://techno-tim.github.io/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="https://techno-tim.github.io/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Techno Tim </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Linux desktop, inside of a container, inside of a browser??? Yes. A Webtop.</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux desktop, inside of a container, inside of a browser??? Yes. A Webtop." /><published>2021-06-20T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-06-20T11:07:58-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Have you ever thought about running a Linux desktop inside of a container? Me neither until I found this awesome project from LinuxServer called Webtops. A webtop is a technology stack that allows you to run Ubuntu or Alpine Linux within a container that is fully accessible from a browser. This allows you to use most Linux features with a container with a fraction of the cost of resources.... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>2 Factor Auth and Single Sign on with Authelia</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Factor Auth and Single Sign on with Authelia" /><published>2021-06-05T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-06-06T15:42:15-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="traefik" /> <summary> Authelia is an open source Single Sign On and 2FA companion for reverse proxies. It helps you secure your endpoints with single factor and 2 factor auth. It works with Nginx, Traefik, and HA proxy. Today, we’ll configure Authelia with Portainer and Traefik and have 2 Factor up and running with brute force protection! Watch Video Traefik Authelia will work with other reverse proxies but ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Is adding 3 MILLION domains to your Pi-Hole Block List a good thing?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is adding 3 MILLION domains to your Pi-Hole Block List a good thing?" /><published>2021-05-08T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-06-05T09:35:10-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> In some of my previous Pi-Hole videos many of you spotted my blocklist with over a millions sites added and you wondered how you can do the same. Well, today I show you how to block more ads, block more tracking, block more malware, and block more telemetry with these community lists. Bonus (and spoiler alert) I show you how to add 3.5 million! Thanks to Firebog for the great lists firebog... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Put Wildcard Certificates and SSL on EVERYTHING</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Put Wildcard Certificates and SSL on EVERYTHING" /><published>2021-04-24T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-25T23:42:39-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="traefik" /> <summary> Today, we’re going to use SSL for everything. No more self-sign certs. No more http. No more hosting things on odd ports. We’re going all in with SSL for our internal services and our external services too. We going to set up a reverse proxy using Traefik, Portainer, and use that to get wildcard certificates from Let’s Encrypt. Join me and let’s secure all the things. Watch Video Docke... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Using Pi-Hole for Local DNS - Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Pi-Hole for Local DNS - Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide" /><published>2021-04-17T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-06-05T09:35:10-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Pi-Hole is a wonderful ad blocking DNS sever for your network, but did you know you can also use it for a Local DNS server? In this fast, simple, and easy guide we’ll walk through how to create DNS Entries (A Records) for the clients on your network and also set up Aliases (pointers to A Records) so that you can start using DNS at home instead of relying on IP addresses. Watch Video command... </summary> </entry> </feed>
